So what is a genre.
那么什么是流派。
Well this genre is a type or a kind of something that's what it is.
好吧，这种类型是一种类型或某种东西，就是这样。
We use it not for everything.
我们并非将其用于所有事情。
We don't say a genre of fruit for example.
例如，我们不会说一种水果。
We don't use it for objects.
我们不将它用于对象。
We use it usually for movies.
我们通常将它用于电影。
We use it for TV.
我们将它用于电视。
Similar entertainment videos online literature books other types of other types of literature and we
类似的娱乐视频 网络文学书籍 其他类型的其他类型的文学和我们
use it for music.
用它来听音乐。
Now the ones that we use for literature and movies or literature and TV series they're often the same
现在我们用于文学和电影或文学和电视剧的那些通常是相同的
not in every case but they're often the same or similar music.
并非在所有情况下，但它们通常是相同或相似的音乐。
Of course the genres are very very different.
当然，流派是非常非常不同的。
You do not have for example rock and roll literature.
你没有例如摇滚文学。
That would be very silly.
那将是非常愚蠢的。
That would be a genre of music.
那将是一种音乐类型。
OK.
好的。
So let's talk about some of the common movie genres and we can we can use them in different ways.
因此，让我们谈谈一些常见的电影类型，我们可以以不同的方式使用它们。
Let's just go through what they mean and what kind of movie they represent.
让我们来看看它们的含义以及它们代表的电影类型。
OK so let's first talk about action.
好的，让我们先谈谈行动。
One of the interesting things about genres is sometimes one part of a genre can stand by itself but
关于体裁的一个有趣的事情是，有时一个体裁的一部分可以独立存在，但
you often see them put together for example if we look at action and adventure you can have an action
你经常看到它们放在一起，例如，如果我们看动作和冒险，你可以有一个动作
movie a movie with a lot of car chases for example maybe a car chase a movie with maybe explosions or
电影 一部有很多汽车追逐的电影，例如，一部汽车追逐一部可能有爆炸的电影，或者
war.
战争。
This would be an action movie maybe a lot of kung fu or fighting but an action adventure movie is a
这将是一部动作片，可能有很多功夫或战斗，但动作冒险片是
little bit a little bit more than that.
比这多一点点。
It maybe has a maybe a story where the characters go somewhere far away and do something crazy.
它可能有一个故事，其中角色到很远的地方做一些疯狂的事情。
So there's action but there's also adventure pop action adventure so we mix these up in fact now romantic
所以有动作，但也有冒险流行动作冒险，所以我们把这些混合起来，实际上现在很浪漫
comedy is similar.
喜剧也类似。
So if we said a romantic film a romantic film that could go by itself sometimes romance.
因此，如果我们说一部浪漫电影，它是一部可以独立发展的浪漫电影，有时是浪漫的。
But that's usually used for literature then a romantic comedy is also very common which is funny.
但这通常用于文学，然后浪漫喜剧也很常见，这很有趣。
Comedy means means it's funny and you can have comedy by itself.
喜剧意味着它很有趣，你可以自己拥有喜剧。
So if it's just supposed to make you laugh and that's the point of the movie it's a comedy.
所以如果它只是为了让你发笑，这就是这部电影的重点，它就是一部喜剧。
OK but if it has a love story as well and it's funny then it's a romantic comedy.
好的，但如果它也有爱情故事而且很有趣，那么它就是一部浪漫喜剧。
Now if it's just a love story and it's a very serious and it's not funny at all.
现在，如果这只是一个爱情故事，而且非常严肃，一点也不好笑。
Well maybe maybe it's a drama.
好吧，也许这是一部戏剧。
So we often hear TV drama a drama is usually more serious.
所以我们经常听到电视剧一出戏通常比较严肃。
It's not supposed to be funny.
这不应该是有趣的。
Maybe there are some funny things in it but that's not what it's about right.
也许其中有一些有趣的东西，但这不是正确的。
All right thriller and horror.
好吧，惊悚片和恐怖片。
So what's the difference between these these are two types of what we would call Scary scary movies
那么这些有什么区别？这是我们称之为恐怖电影的两种类型
a movie that makes you feel scared might make you feel scared in different ways.
一部让你感到害怕的电影可能会让你以不同的方式感到害怕。
If there's a lot of blood and violence and torture and terrible things horrible things then we call
如果有很多鲜血、暴力、酷刑和可怕的事情，那么我们称之为可怕的事情
it a horror film a horror film.
这是一部恐怖片恐怖片。
These are often a bit more maybe disgusting said Gee you're a bit more disgusting maybe there's a lot
这些通常有点恶心，说 哎呀，你有点恶心，也许有很多
more blood a thriller may just be exciting.
更多的血腥惊悚片可能只是令人兴奋。
So if you are watching a thriller movie maybe something suddenly jumps out and you go wow that's very
所以，如果你正在看一部惊悚片，可能突然有什么东西跳出来，你会哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇
exciting.
令人兴奋。
But it's not horror.
但这不是恐怖。
Exactly.
确切地。
So they're both scary movies but they're kind of different in the style right sometimes maybe they're
所以它们都是恐怖电影，但它们的风格有点不同，有时也许它们是
mixed.
混合。
But a movie is usually either called a thriller or a horror movie.
但是电影通常被称为惊悚片或恐怖片。
So what's the difference between sci fi or science fiction.
那么科幻和科幻小说有什么区别。
This is also called science fiction and fantasy.
这也叫科幻和幻想。
What's the difference.
有什么不同。
Well science fiction or sci fi and it usually is called sci fi for movies although for maybe a novel
好吧，科幻小说或科幻小说，它通常被称为电影科幻小说，尽管可能是小说
it's often called science fiction.
它通常被称为科幻小说。
The full name if it's a sci fi movie or a sci fi maybe novel it's about something that may be possible
科幻电影或科幻小说的全名，它是关于可能发生的事情
but it's either in the future or it doesn't exist now.
但它要么在未来，要么现在不存在。
And it's some amazing technology or it involves space travel which again may be possible but we just
这是一些了不起的技术，或者它涉及太空旅行，这又是可能的，但我们只是
don't see it around us now.
现在在我们周围看不到它。
So crazy technology.
如此疯狂的技术。
Technology like laser guns and all that stuff.
诸如激光枪之类的技术和所有这些东西。
Alien space travel.
外星人太空旅行。
This is usually sci fi fantasy is different because fantasy has magic in it.
这通常与科幻奇幻不同，因为奇幻中有魔力。
Maybe fantasy is about a very old world but it involves something magical.
也许幻想是关于一个非常古老的世界，但它涉及一些神奇的东西。
For example Harry Potter would be considered fantasy or maybe its action adventure fantasy.
例如，哈利波特将被认为是幻想，或者可能是它的动作冒险幻想。
You could put all those together because it has magic.
您可以将所有这些放在一起，因为它具有魔力。
It's not about technology.
这与技术无关。
So that's the difference between sci fi and fantasy although they sometimes are mixed and it's difficult
这就是科幻和奇幻之间的区别，尽管它们有时是混合的，而且很难
to tell which one it is.
告诉它是哪一个。
Usually it'll be called either a sci fi movie or a fantasy movie even though sometimes they might be
通常它会被称为科幻电影或奇幻电影，尽管有时它们可​​能是
close to the line.
靠近线。
Then a documentary is anything that's about real life.
那么纪录片就是关于现实生活的任何东西。
That doesn't mean there can't be anything not real in it.
这并不意味着其中不可能有任何不真实的东西。
So for example if you watch a documentary maybe it's about a historical event something that happened
举个例子，如果你看一部纪录片，它可能是关于一个历史事件的
in history.
在历史上。
Maybe it's about a historical event and in the documentary there are some scenes that are done by actors
也许是关于一个历史事件，在纪录片中，有些场景是由演员完成的
right.
正确的。
So we say it's dramatized but it's about a real event.
所以我们说它是戏剧化的，但它是关于一个真实的事件。
Or maybe it's about animals.
或者也许是关于动物的。
If it's a story about animals who speak then OK it's not but if it's about real animals and they're
如果这是一个关于会说话的动物的故事，那没关系，但如果它是关于真正的动物的，而且它们是
saying all the animals this time of you that eat the grass and that kind of movie that is a documentary
说你这次吃草的所有动物和那种纪录片
documentary TV series documentary movie.
纪录片电视连续剧纪录片。
I personally like documentaries very much because I think it's a good way to learn about interesting
我个人非常喜欢纪录片，因为我认为这是学习有趣的好方法
topics that I can't really see every day.
我每天都看不到的话题。
I can't always go to Africa and look at lions hunting other animals in the wild.
我不能总是去非洲看狮子在野外捕猎其他动物。
Right.
正确的。
So a documentary is a good way to kind of experience that and learn about it.
因此，纪录片是一种体验和了解它的好方法。
These are not all the genres that you'll see.
这些并不是您会看到的所有类型。
You'll see others as well and you'll see them mixed around in other ways too.
你也会看到其他人，你也会看到他们以其他方式混在一起。
But I want you to just be aware of some of the very common genres and how we talk about them.
但我希望您了解一些非常常见的类型以及我们如何谈论它们。
Next we'll talk about some specific phrases we can use when we're describing movies and the people who
接下来我们将讨论一些在描述电影和电影的人时可以使用的特定短语
are in the movies.
在电影中。